<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on Decode</title>
    <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on Decode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:37:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>遗嘱</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/04/%E9%81%97%E5%98%B1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:37:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/04/%E9%81%97%E5%98%B1/</guid>
      <description>如果我突然离世，我会有什么最后的话想跟这个世界说的呢？</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>habit</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/23/habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 22:55:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/23/habit/</guid>
      <description>Everything is a habit. Depression is a habit. Being confident is a habit. Failing is a habit. Making money is a habit. Gambling is a habit. Saving evry bit of money is a habit. Quiting is a habit.
You are just so used to it that you don&amp;rsquo;t feel it when you do it.
Anxiety is also a habit. When you talk about changing, you are talking about quiting a habit and build up a new habit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Create the Meaning</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:22:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</guid>
      <description>The meaning of life, this is the thing everyone thinks now and then. I thought about it a lot (perhaps too much) when I was in high school. And that was the worst time of my life so far.
Later, for no reason, I let go of the question (what is the meaning of life) and tried to walk the road of life as a common guy.
Today, after so many years, the answer of that question have flashed in my head many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is an experience</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:13:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</guid>
      <description>We can live only once. All in all, your experience determines the quality of your life. That is to say, it is subjective (not objective). So we can fool ourselves into a better life.
You have the most compeletely life if you experienced the most kinds of lives, good, bad, happy, unhappy, dangerous, safe, poor or rich, girl or boy.
But, that is a slippery slope. You can have the experience of a murderer and be sentenced to death.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
