<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on null</title>
    <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on null</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eastwell</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/11/20/eastwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/11/20/eastwell/</guid>
      <description>It has been almost two month since we moved to this small village. It was not until two days ago that I found out on Wikipedia that there has been only 60 to 150 people living here since 1850s.&#xA;不到一百人的小村庄，其实就我们在村里路上散步见到的人来说，应该都不到二十个人。&#xA;村里到镇上有一趟公交，我们称之为村级公交，因为第一次我们去镇上回来的时候，公车是反向开的，就是绕着周围的村子走一圈，再回到这个村里，花了四十分钟左右。直接往回开的话，只需要十五分钟左右。但不论哪个方向车上的人都不多，而且坐得多了，坐车的都是熟悉的面孔了。都是一些上了年纪的爷爷奶奶，很友好，见面会寒暄几句。虽然我们听力一般，说的也不好，但总归能聊几句的。&#xA;村里没有商店，唯一的一个蔬菜摊子，就是我们住的地方那条路出来左手边有一个小车，上面一个简单的棚子，旁边一个招牌上写着，“Fresh Vegi Licolnshire?”, 小车上一些常见的蔬菜，胡萝卜，土豆，花菜，孢子甘蓝，苏格兰大葱，等等。我们也没买过几次。只买过一次土豆，万圣节前买了一个大南瓜，巨大无比，我们煮粥，炒菜，前后吃了一个月才消灭干净。&#xA;村子被两条公路分成了四部分，公交站就在十字路口的第一象限。路上车不多，但没有人行道，车开得也不慢，出去散步的时候总提心吊胆的。&#xA;村子里的风景没的说，我们住的房子旁边是一大片草地，两个月里也没见放羊，也没什么别的活动，就那么放着。房子后面是也是好几片草地连着，每天都有马在吃草，天气转凉，马后面都穿上了衣服，颇可爱。&#xA;后面发现，马场后面的的棚子里还养了几头大黑猪。棚子后面是一个养牛场，每次路过的时候，牛粪的味道清新扑鼻，熏得人沉醉。再往后就都是大片的放牧的草场了，每一片都有高高的篱笆围着，这里的篱笆都是植物修剪长成的，大概有两米多高，宽一米左右。所以基本看不到后面，只有到了草场锁着的铁门才能看到里面的景象，蓝天，白云，草场的小坡起起伏伏，有时候会有牛在吃草，或站，或躺，你出声喊，很多牛都会转过头看着你，呆呆的。&#xA;两个月里，这个十字路口的四个方向我们都走过好多次了，虽然后面天气冷了，出去的少，但基本周围近的两个村子也都去过了，一个稍微热闹些，有些商店和活动，一个就更显冷清，幽邃。想想两个都不近，单程有两三公里吧。&#xA;When we first came here, the host told us, &amp;ldquo;My son called this place Sleepwell.&amp;rdquo; Haha, indeed, it is super quiet during the night.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distrohop</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/11/13/distrohop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/11/13/distrohop/</guid>
      <description>最近闲来无事，又开始了大学时候就一直玩得停不下来的Linux系统安装实验，感觉自己有病。&#xA;Tried Manjaro, Pop!OS, Fedora, OpenSuse, Ubuntu, etc. One thing I have to say is they have advanced alot since the last time I played (that was Ubuntu 6/8.04, around 2009 or so). Media codecs and Chinese IME are all working properly. Though some apps require some tweaking a bit, most of the functions people expect from a working laptop are okay.&#xA;Based on the distrohop, I have below conclusions:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Countdown Timer</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/10/19/a-countdown-timer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/10/19/a-countdown-timer/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by a macro in Keyboard Maestro, I asked ChatGPT to create a simple countdown timer in Python.&#xA;To use it, save the script as show_countdown.py, then simply run the script with an integer (how many minutes to count down) like:&#xA;python show_countdown.py 5 # 5 minutes countdown timer The script is:&#xA;import webbrowser def show_countdown(minutes): html_content = f&#39;&#39;&#39; &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&amp;quot;en&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;UTF-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Countdown Timer&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;style&amp;gt; body {{ font-family: Fira Mono, Monaco, Menlo, monospace; font-size: 10em; font-weight: bold; text-align: center; background-color: aliceblue; transition: background-color 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TTS with edge-tts</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/10/19/tts-with-edge-tts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/10/19/tts-with-edge-tts/</guid>
      <description>I like the read out loud in Edge browser on MacOS, but it&amp;rsquo;s not available in Linux. Luckily, there is a edge-tts created by rany2 on Github.&#xA;So, I asked ChatGPT create several scripts to read out the clipboard and convert a txt file to audio.&#xA;Dependencies: python, pip, pipx, edge-tts, xclip. Took me sometime to install all the deps. Then to use the scripts, just copy some text and run the bash script.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/08/11/100-days-of-swiftui/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/08/11/100-days-of-swiftui/</guid>
      <description>Has been learning Swift for the last couple of days. Day 9 of 100 Days of SwiftUI.&#xA;Today, when trying to solve the quiz of finding the square root of a given number (without using the built-in sqrt()), I learned the binary search algorithm in Swift.&#xA;The core codes:&#xA;var low = 1 var high = number var result = 0 while low &amp;lt;= high { let mid = (low + high) / 2 if mid * mid == number { return mid } else if mid * mid &amp;lt; number { low = mid + 1 result = mid } else { high = mid - 1 } } It&amp;rsquo;s kind of interesting, so I tried to write the binary search in Swift (finding the index of a given target in a given array).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RIP Nao</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/07/27/rip-nao/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/07/27/rip-nao/</guid>
      <description>妈跟我说孬没了。&#xA;它刚来家里的时候，脾气很坏，会喉咙低沉地吼，还会咬人。虽然只是轻轻地咬。可能是应激反应吧。当时还录了个视频，“跑两步就喘”，是当时我在视频里说的。现在回头看看，可能小家伙就是特别怕热。&#xA;来的时候还只是个小奶猫，后来脾气慢慢变好，慢慢地不哼哼了，也不咬人了。可以抱着，手感一级棒。熟悉了吧。虽然笨，但是学东西挺快，跟着家里的大猫，有样学样，什么都会了。再后来，甚至一米多高的窗台都能助跑然后跳上去了。要知道它是个只有30厘米左右的高的小短腿儿。&#xA;小家伙出门不怕生，带出去敢走。有一次大早上带去茅家埠，杭州湿热的夏天，太热了，我们索性把它放在水里，小家伙动作标准地游起泳来。很厉害。虽然腿短，划起水来动作十分滑稽。不过虽然腿短，小家伙非常能跑，跑起来小短腿蹬在地上咚咚响。但也追不上彪就是了。虽然越短，脾气还很横，经常不服气大猫，然后被彪按在地上摩擦，大声求饶。&#xA;从杭州开车回家里，一路上大猫各种叫，小家伙安安静静，一声不吭，自得其乐。因为出国，不得不把两个小东西放在家里，让爸妈帮忙养着。过了没一个月，说小短腿上了二楼，然后就丢了，好几天了，都没找到。都打算放弃了，准备接受小家伙走丢了的事实。但最后在二彪的坚持下，妈又去让隔壁邻居在家里找了一遍，最后在厕所门后的管道地下找到了，孬子头朝里，屁股朝外，一声不吭。想想胆小的它可能已经保持这样的姿势好几天了。被爸抱了回去。&#xA;胆小，又“豪横”，腿短，但爱动，能吃，能睡，虽然笨，但学习能力强。这就是孬吧。可爱的小家伙。&#xA;前两天妈跟我说小猫的肚子一喘一喘的，我没当回事，以为忍忍过两天天气凉了就好了。然后妈发了个让人不忍再看第二遍的视频过来，我看了下才发现事情有点严重，赶紧让他们给它擦擦水，降降温。没什么用，今天早上发来消息说没了。&#xA;呜呼！生死我们都无法选择，谁又想来到这世间过一遍这酸甜苦辣，孬也算解脱了。&#xA;I will hold dear the memory of you. May you rest in peace. Love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TIL: Typed.js</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/07/22/til-typed.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/post/2023/07/22/til-typed.js/</guid>
      <description>Today, I learned how to use react-typed. It is really simple, but the result is quite fancy.&#xA;You can get a typewriter effect and deletion effect with simple code like below (in a react project):&#xA;import React from &#39;react&#39;; import Typed from &#39;react-typed&#39;; const Hero = () =&amp;gt; { return ( &amp;lt;div className=&#39;text-white&#39;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You can easily earn money for&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Typed strings={[&#39;me&#39;, &#39;you&#39;, &#39;all&#39;]} typeSpeed={120} backSpeed={160} loop /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; ) } export default Hero So I did a search and found that react-typed is a wrapper around the original Typed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
