<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on null</title>
    <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on null</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing &amp;</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/journal/2025/03/20/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/journal/2025/03/20/writing/</guid>
      <description>It has been a long time that I rarely use my laptop, because I am working. Labour intensive work. So intensive that I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to use it? NO. You think it&amp;rsquo;s starts to lose its meaning.&#xA;AI? Writing? News? Nothing really matters anymore. I just get up, work, play games, eat, sleep. That&amp;rsquo;s it. I don&amp;rsquo;t need to use laptop. I can&amp;rsquo;t make sufficient money to support my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding jobs is not easy &amp;</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/journal/2024/05/31/finding-jobs-is-not-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/journal/2024/05/31/finding-jobs-is-not-easy/</guid>
      <description>自从回到这里已经两个月了，一直在找工作，到现在还是没有着落。目前只有两个口译的兼职，没什么活，块儿八毛的根本不够吃穿。愁煞人。&#xA;投的都是一些 burger flipper 的简单工作竟然都没有回应，无话可说：&#xA;Five Guys, no reply McDonalds, pass screening, no interview Tesco, no reply Morrison, John Lewis, no reply Amazon, no reply Lidi, no reply yet Aldi, passed 3 rounds, final round next week. 只有一个奥乐齐有点眉目，但还有最后一关。找个超市理货员的工作都要这么好几轮的面试吗？网上有很多人吐槽，我心里也是各种不满。申请的时候先有一轮测试题，过了之后才能填申请表，填完申请表，过了一周发邮件说有个视频面试，就是录制一些自己的回答问题的视频上传，三个问题，各一分钟。然后又过一周，单独面试。面试的时候我记得说要24小时内回复，但过了一周才有消息，说下周三店内体验。这三周就过去了。看网上说，这个体验完还有一周都没收到邮件的。&#xA;如此长的流程，不知道的以为在招聘 VP 呢。当然了，这比那些不回复的还是要好很多的。&#xA;PS. 来了只猫，取名招财，太需要招财了。另外，昨天家里定了车，秦普拉斯。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the life of human</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/19/on-the-life-of-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 17:51:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/19/on-the-life-of-human/</guid>
      <description>人一生下来就开始了一个无法停下来的“生产线”。你必须吃东西，然后就会拉。一开始还有有人喂你吃，找来食物给你吃，等大了，你就需要自己找吃的了，为了吃的，你就必须得找个工作做，赚钱，吃东西，拉。这个过程永远停不下来，知道你不需要吃了，你死了。&#xA;而且，只要人活着就会产生垃圾，一刻不停。因为你吃完就会拉，甚至不吃也会。然后吃的东西会产生垃圾。人体也会有各种分泌物。然后你自己为了寻找吃的，为了赚钱买吃的，还会产生更多的垃圾。所有这些，换位成地球，我都觉得头大。好烦啊。</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Create the Meaning</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:22:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</guid>
      <description>The meaning of life, this is the thing everyone thinks now and then. I thought about it a lot (perhaps too much) when I was in high school. And that was the worst time of my life so far.&#xA;Later, for no reason, I let go of the question (what is the meaning of life) and tried to walk the road of life as a common guy.&#xA;Today, after so many years, the answer of that question have flashed in my head many times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life is an experience</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:13:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</guid>
      <description>We can live only once. All in all, your experience determines the quality of your life. That is to say, it is subjective (not objective). So we can fool ourselves into a better life.&#xA;You have the most compeletely life if you experienced the most kinds of lives, good, bad, happy, unhappy, dangerous, safe, poor or rich, girl or boy.&#xA;But, that is a slippery slope. You can have the experience of a murderer and be sentenced to death.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
