<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Decode</title>
    <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Decode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>No Autopilot Life</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/18/no-autopilot-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/18/no-autopilot-life/</guid>
      <description>You need to stop and look at your own life every now and then, otherwise it will slip into autopilot mode, which is really bad.
You would pick up the addiction you spent so long to quit. And all the momentum you built up will be gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>遗嘱</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/04/%E9%81%97%E5%98%B1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:37:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/04/%E9%81%97%E5%98%B1/</guid>
      <description>如果我突然离世，我会有什么最后的话想跟这个世界说的呢？</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mallorca</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/03/mallorca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 01:07:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/03/mallorca/</guid>
      <description>Still at the airport of Mallorca. Delayed for more than 3 hours. Shouldnt say that the last delay was the longest. Skin was burned on the head, back and chest. Need time to heal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/29/barcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 19:28:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/29/barcelona/</guid>
      <description>@BCN Airport now. Flight delayed for more than 1 hour already. Still waiting. Wasted a whole afternoon here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/28/amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:24:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/28/amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>On the vueling plane from Amsterdam to Barcelona.
For the last two days, we were in Amsterdam. Not a very pleasant tour at the beginning I have to say. We were stopped by the sulky girl at border control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>habit</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/23/habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 22:55:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/23/habit/</guid>
      <description>Everything is a habit. Depression is a habit. Being confident is a habit. Failing is a habit. Making money is a habit. Gambling is a habit. Saving evry bit of money is a habit. Quiting is a habit.
You are just so used to it that you don&amp;rsquo;t feel it when you do it.
Anxiety is also a habit. When you talk about changing, you are talking about quiting a habit and build up a new habit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Create the Meaning</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:22:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</guid>
      <description>The meaning of life, this is the thing everyone thinks now and then. I thought about it a lot (perhaps too much) when I was in high school. And that was the worst time of my life so far.
Later, for no reason, I let go of the question (what is the meaning of life) and tried to walk the road of life as a common guy.
Today, after so many years, the answer of that question have flashed in my head many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is an experience</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:13:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</guid>
      <description>We can live only once. All in all, your experience determines the quality of your life. That is to say, it is subjective (not objective). So we can fool ourselves into a better life.
You have the most compeletely life if you experienced the most kinds of lives, good, bad, happy, unhappy, dangerous, safe, poor or rich, girl or boy.
But, that is a slippery slope. You can have the experience of a murderer and be sentenced to death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>feel bad</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/2023-06-15-feel-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 18:42:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/2023-06-15-feel-bad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo Ivy</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/about/</guid>
      <description>This Hugo theme was ported from Ivy, a minimalist website generator built in Python. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to document this theme. You have to read the source code to understand what it can do. All I can say for now is that I love it. It is clean, minimal, and responsive.
I hope you will enjoy this theme. The source code is on Github. Happy hacking!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
