<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Decode</title>
    <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Decode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Create the Meaning</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:22:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</guid>
      <description>The meaning of life, this is the thing everyone thinks now and then. I thought about it a lot (perhaps too much) when I was in high school. And that was the worst time of my life so far.
Later, for no reason, I let go of the question (what is the meaning of life) and tried to walk the road of life as a common guy.
Today, after so many years, the answer of that question have flashed in my head many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is an experience</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:13:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</guid>
      <description>We can live only once. All in all, your experience determines the quality of your life. That is to say, it is subjective (not objective). So we can fool ourselves into a better life.
You have the most compeletely life if you experienced the most kinds of lives, good, bad, happy, unhappy, dangerous, safe, poor or rich, girl or boy.
But, that is a slippery slope. You can have the experience of a murderer and be sentenced to death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>feel bad</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/2023-06-15-feel-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 18:42:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/2023-06-15-feel-bad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo Ivy</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/about/</guid>
      <description>This Hugo theme was ported from Ivy, a minimalist website generator built in Python. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to document this theme. You have to read the source code to understand what it can do. All I can say for now is that I love it. It is clean, minimal, and responsive.
I hope you will enjoy this theme. The source code is on Github. Happy hacking!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
