<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>note on Decode</title>
    <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/categories/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in note on Decode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/categories/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Flight&#39; Mode</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/08/03/flight-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/08/03/flight-mode/</guid>
      <description>Fight or flight? Flight, of course.
每隔一段时间都会陷入一种“逃避”模式，that is &amp;ldquo;Flight&amp;rdquo; Mode。看到邮件、消息，心里会很怕，很沉重，不愿意回复。什么正事也不愿意做，不愿意直面自己，不愿意改简历，不愿意申请工作，不愿意上班，不愿意赚钱，反正就是什么“正事”都不想做，逃避这个，逃避那个，逃避一切。逃避可耻，也没用。因为逃避到最后，你该面对的还是要面对，所以该直面还是早点直面好。
Face it, you can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;flight&amp;rdquo; all your life.
当然，道理都懂，并不代表就会行动。现在想想，其实这种模式和“Auto Pilot”的模式是一样的，随意地生活，慢慢就会随波逐流，慢慢就会变得麻木。经得起审视的人生才值得度过。所以人生是需要一些刻意的。这么想想，做人可太累了。要自己不断地向上，才能保持在原地。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aversion to Changes</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/30/aversion-to-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/30/aversion-to-changes/</guid>
      <description>最近感觉自己越来越惧怕改变。可能是变老的一个迹象吧。年轻的时候看到什么都是新鲜的，想更深入的了解。很喜欢去没去过的地方，旅行到了一个地方，总想着到处转转，看看不一样的风景。前几天去欧洲的时候，或者更早的时候，我已经明显地感觉到，现在到了一个陌生的地方，只会感到累，感到陌生，一丝丝的恐惧，以及一些“不情愿”。不再愿意花时间去体验了。
我想这就是最明显的一个变老的迹象吧。看到了所以地方千篇一律的地方，很少会看到特别新鲜的东西了。我到现在还是最喜欢杭州。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes from Dune</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/27/quotes-from-dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/27/quotes-from-dune/</guid>
      <description>Today, I had the chance to watch the movie Dune. While the plot may be straightforward, the film&amp;rsquo;s captivating tempo and storytelling truly grabbed my attention. So I took note of several thought-provoking lines.
On Life: “The mystery of life isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem to solve, but a reality to experience.”
On Fear:
“I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration. I will face my fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the life of human</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/19/on-the-life-of-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 17:51:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/19/on-the-life-of-human/</guid>
      <description>人一生下来就开始了一个无法停下来的“生产线”。你必须吃东西，然后就会拉。一开始还有有人喂你吃，找来食物给你吃，等大了，你就需要自己找吃的了，为了吃的，你就必须得找个工作做，赚钱，吃东西，拉。这个过程永远停不下来，知道你不需要吃了，你死了。
而且，只要人活着就会产生垃圾，一刻不停。因为你吃完就会拉，甚至不吃也会。然后吃的东西会产生垃圾。人体也会有各种分泌物。然后你自己为了寻找吃的，为了赚钱买吃的，还会产生更多的垃圾。所有这些，换位成地球，我都觉得头大。好烦啊。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Therapy</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/18/writing-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 22:48:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/18/writing-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Writing is relaxing.
When you feel drown by anxiety, just sit down and start writing something. About what? It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. There is paid classes on social media called &amp;ldquo;mindful writing&amp;rdquo;. Though I would never pay for that, but I agree with the idea behind the classes. Writing is the easiest way to get into the &amp;ldquo;flowing&amp;rdquo; state, which is sought after by most people who practice mindful related things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Autopilot Life</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/18/no-autopilot-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/18/no-autopilot-life/</guid>
      <description>You need to stop and look at your own life every now and then, otherwise it will slip into autopilot mode, which is really bad.
You would pick up the addiction you spent so long to quit. And all the momentum you built up will be gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Will</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/04/my-will/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 22:37:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/04/my-will/</guid>
      <description>如果我突然离世，我会有什么最后的话想跟这个世界说的呢？
最近在推特上关注的一个技术圈的大佬忽然离世，让我颇为震动。虽然并不认识，但就好像是前几天的晚上还看到他在发布一些日常的状态，然后突然人没了，这个账号永远再也不会更新了。他是不是还有些话想说呢？
其实我自己并不害怕“死亡”，我更怕的其实是周围人的“死亡”，那些自己熟悉的人突然消失不见了。这个让人不知道该如何面对，如何接受。
想想如果自己突然心梗，会有什么话还要说吗？有什么没做的想做的事已经不重要了，所以到了现在这个年纪忽然就要想想该写遗书了？把自己特别想说的话先写下来，这样自己突然噶了也就没什么需要死不瞑目了。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mallorca</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/03/mallorca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 01:07:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/07/03/mallorca/</guid>
      <description>Still at the airport of Mallorca. Delayed for more than 3 hours. Shouldnt say that the last delay was the longest. Skin was burned on the head, back and chest. Need time to heal.
It turned out to be the longest delay I&amp;rsquo;ve ever experienced till now. We didn&amp;rsquo;t arrive at London till 3 am. Then we had to wait till 10am for the bus because that&amp;rsquo;s the earliest bus to my place (rail service was on strike that day).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/29/barcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 19:28:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/29/barcelona/</guid>
      <description>@BCN Airport now. Flight delayed for more than 1 hour already. Still waiting. Wasted a whole afternoon here.
之前在Ins上看到过很多巴塞罗那的照片，全都是暖色调的，整整齐齐的城市等等。这次来转了一天多一点，并没有什么好印象。人太多了，天气又热，作为游客，公共交通上人多的一塌糊涂。从来没座儿。
去了高迪的圣家堂，很高，很惊艳，外面和里面的设计都很牛。这就是《文明》游戏里面所谓的人类历史上的“奇观”吧。另外的，并没有什么留下深刻的印象。还去了毕加索博物馆，一个小巷子里面，都是手稿，买票的时候，工作人员给了学生票，15欧。出来之后在巷子里旁边的一家小店吃了东西，60欧。菜单全都看不懂。
住在海边的一个酒店，挺远，设备挺老，挺不爽的是当天酒店的预订价格竟然比自己提前一个月订的要便宜。旁边5分钟就可以走到海边，柏油路晒得热热的。彪的鞋子不合脚，脚破了，后来就索性光着脚走了。
海边人很多，第二天看日出的时候发现竟然有人搭了帐篷就住在沙滩上。因为第二天就要收拾东西走了，所以就没有多转。在酒店旁边的一个饭馆吃了饭，海鲜饭咸死。其他还好，油煎辣椒不错。交通不方便。米兰之家巴蒂略之家都没去，然后桂尔公园大老远去了没有票了，就只好悻悻坐车去赶飞机了。
什么破地方。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amsterdam</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/28/amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 09:24:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/28/amsterdam/</guid>
      <description>On the vueling plane from Amsterdam to Barcelona.
For the last two days, we were in Amsterdam. Not a very pleasant tour at the beginning I have to say. We were stopped by the sulky girl at border control.
因为在海关被拦住，所以心情一直很差。住在城市边缘一个火车站边上的酒店，交通还算方便，相比起英国的破公共交通，荷兰的真的算是堪比国内了，火车、地铁、轻轨、公交车一应俱全，虽然价格比较贵就是了。
现在回想起来，可能在荷兰的两天算是真正的游客状态。去了国家博物馆，梵高没有票了所以没去，去了风车村，很小一些村子，随便转了转，坐了一圈运河的船。吃了猪肘子，没吃完打包，回去又吃了一顿才吃掉。然后还吃了很贵的湖南米线，然后去了旁边的红灯街，因为没去小粉象所以彪一直拉着脸。我也不知道有什么好看的。
第三天一大早坐火车去机场赶巴塞罗那的飞机，比较幸运，没怎么延误。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All is Habit</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/23/all-is-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 22:55:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/23/all-is-habit/</guid>
      <description>Everything is a habit. Depression is a habit. Being confident is a habit. Failing is a habit. Making money is a habit. Gambling is a habit. Saving evry bit of money is a habit. Quiting is a habit.
You are just so used to it that you don&amp;rsquo;t feel it when you do it.
Anxiety is also a habit. When you talk about changing, you are talking about quiting a habit and build up a new habit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Create the Meaning</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:22:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/you-create-the-meaning/</guid>
      <description>The meaning of life, this is the thing everyone thinks now and then. I thought about it a lot (perhaps too much) when I was in high school. And that was the worst time of my life so far.
Later, for no reason, I let go of the question (what is the meaning of life) and tried to walk the road of life as a common guy.
Today, after so many years, the answer of that question have flashed in my head many times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is an experience</title>
      <link>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 19:13:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dearbojack.github.io/decode/note/2023/06/18/life-is-an-experience/</guid>
      <description>We can live only once. All in all, your experience determines the quality of your life. That is to say, it is subjective (not objective). So we can fool ourselves into a better life.
You have the most compeletely life if you experienced the most kinds of lives, good, bad, happy, unhappy, dangerous, safe, poor or rich, girl or boy.
But, that is a slippery slope. You can have the experience of a murderer and be sentenced to death.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
